<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cameron DeCoster</title>
    <link>https://camdecoster.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cameron DeCoster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://camdecoster.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mirror Reverse Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/mirror-reverse-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/mirror-reverse-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Alex Lopez on Unsplash
I’ve been going through some practice problems that one is likely to see during a technical interview for a developer position. One that I worked through recently has a problem statement as follows:
Write a function to reverse the order of words in a string in place.
That seems simple enough, except for the last two words, “in place.” That means that you should be mutating the existing array, not creating a new one, which is what I would initially try to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change how a website looks with Stylus and UserCSS</title>
      <link>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/change-how-a-website-looks-with-stylus-and-usercss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/change-how-a-website-looks-with-stylus-and-usercss/</guid>
      <description>When using a website, the way it looks (the way it’s styled) is a result of how the author has set up the CSS rules. These rules describe how the HTML should be displayed to the user in different situations. Most websites do a good job of creating something I find presentable. But sometimes I use a site a lot and start to notice things that bother me. In this case, it was the Pocket Casts web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Engineer is a Problem Solver</title>
      <link>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/an-engineer-is-a-problem-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/an-engineer-is-a-problem-solver/</guid>
      <description>In mid-2018, I found out that my company, Zachry Engineering, was going to be closing two of our other offices and that some layoffs might take place in my office. This obviously killed morale and led me to try to distract myself from the potential negative outcomes.
At the time, I was performing a number of exclusion zone calculations for pneumatic pressure testing of pipe. This kind of testing is dangerous because a lot of energy gets stored in the pipe to get it up to pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooks vs. Classes in React</title>
      <link>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/hooks-vs-classes-in-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://camdecoster.github.io/posts/hooks-vs-classes-in-react/</guid>
      <description>I’m working on building a simple expense tracking site, very creatively named Expense Tracker. I’m building it using React for the front-end and Node/Express for the back-end with data being stored in a PostgreSQL database. Here’s a work in progress screenshot:
The main function of this site is to show you how much you’ve been spending in easy to read tables. I hadn’t needed to use tables with React before, so I started looking into it and found React Table.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
